DONNIE HICKS

FULL STACK DEVELOPER*

Summary

I completed a History degree with highest honours before working in communications and sales for the second largest telecom company in the world. After relocating to Canada I continued as a professional communicator at the City of Toronto for nearly a decade as an Advanced Emergency Medical Dispatcher. Wishing to grow outside of that role and inspired by the potential of working with software professionally, I transformed my hobby in computers into a career as a Full Stack Developer.

Goal

I am seeking a positive work environment that appreciates my broad skill set and diverse experience, and gives me an opportunity to work with Javascript, React and GraphQL. I am particularly interested in writing code in the Functional Programming paradigm, and generating blazing-fast, static, low-maintenance, secure web applications with the JAM Stack and Serverless architecture.

Employment

Hyxos

Cofounder/Full Stack Developer

March 2013 to Current

In 2013 I cofounded Hyxos Inc. with my wife in order to pursue business projects. In our most recent endeavour I designed and produced the first edition of a card game called TZI using Python to programmatically generate image assets. I created our product website with Javascript and GatsbyJS, building it with React components and querying content data through Gatsby's GraphQL API.

The Brewbox Company Full Stack Developer

Toronto

Toronto

Sept. 2016 to March 2017

I organized and automated the process of synchronizing customer data with Mailchimp through their API for email marketing purposes. I worked with Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL and Javascript to maintain and extend administrative and other backend support features of the company web portal.

The City of Toronto

Toronto

Advanced Emergency Medical Dispatcher

Sept. 2006 to Oct. 2015

Following established medical protocols, I determined the prioritization of incoming 911 calls and administered first-aid and CPR instructions over the phone. Through radio and telephone channels I dispatched ambulances crews and strategically managed departmental resources to ensure paramedic safety and produce optimal patient outcomes.

AT&T (formerly SBC) Billing Specialist

Tulsa, Oklahoma

Sept. 2002 to May 2003

Fielding inbound calls regarding billing questions, I explained policies, billing procedures, and presented product offerings as solutions to customer needs based on personalized profiles.

Projects

www.tzi.cards

February 2019 to Current

A card game inspired by the lunar calendar. TZI Cards reimagines traditional playing cards and explores the ancient Chinese system of Heavenly Stems and Earthly branches. I built the product home page using the Gatsby static site generator library, and deployed it through Netlify. I also designed and produced all of the digital art assets for the product and site.

1hx.ca

October 2009 to Current

A short-link generator based on YOURLS. I have used open source software to keep this personal project alive and running on the internet for almost ten years. Originally served on a shared hosting platform, I have migrated it through different backend configurations multiple times. Currently running on Ubuntu in a VPS, routing through Nginx, SSL through letsencrypt, and data storage with MySQL.

Contact

donnie@hyxos.ca

416-878-4790

♀ Toronto, Ontario, Canada

in donniehicks

y macbraughton

O hyxos

Education

Oral Roberts University

Sept. 1997 to May 2001

BA in History 2001

3.97 GPA Summa Cum Laude Academic Peer Adviser Minors: Philosophy, Modern Hebrew

Lighthouse Oct. to Dec. **Labs** 2015

Web Development Bootcamp

Ruby on Rails PostgreSQL Javascript

Advanced Analytics and Research Lab

Jan. 2018

Citizen Data Scientist I - III

Introduction to Data Science R Programming Language

Skills

Frontend

HTML CSS/SCSS/SASS Markup

Programming Languages

Javascript Python Ruby

Libraries

Gatsby React GraphQL

Frameworks

Rails Diango

Backend

Linux/Unix PostgreSQL/MySQL/SQLite MongoDB SSL/TLS

Hobbies

Playing Guitar and Drums Singing and Songwriting Playing Video and Board Games Bee-Keeping